<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gerben Jacobs</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/</link><description>Recent content on Gerben Jacobs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My ROI stock portfolio experiment</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/my-roi-stock-portfolio-experiment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/my-roi-stock-portfolio-experiment/</guid><description>After reading a bit about multiple well-known investors mentioning how important Return On Invested Capital is, I decided to generate a small portfolio (actually a pie within Trading212) with some metrics.
I used finviz to screen and since they don&amp;rsquo;t have ROIC, I used Return On Investment (ROI). This is a different metric but is the closest option there is. My screening options were as follows:
ROI of 25% or higher Net profit margin of 25% or higher Market cap of 2 billion or higher Positive dividend Average trading volume of 1 million So the important values are the ROI and net profit margins.</description></item><item><title>svc; an opinionated Go service framework</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/svc-an-opinionated-go-service-framework/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/svc-an-opinionated-go-service-framework/</guid><description>I have been writing Go (or Golang) for about 6 years now. In that time I&amp;rsquo;ve seen quite a few different ways on how to organize a Go project. During my time at MessageBird I got introduced to a nice layered approach. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken those lessons and applied them to something that feels right for me; github.com/gerbenjacobs/svc
svc svc is not an actual framework, but more a convention for creating microservices.</description></item><item><title>First month at GitHub</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/first-month-at-github/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/first-month-at-github/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a month since I joined GitHub in February of 2022. I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying myself a lot, but I&amp;rsquo;m also not sure if the reality has set in completely.
In 2014 I started my first tech job and remember that I went to a conference and got GitHub stickers, they were awesome and all ended up on my MacBook. Eight years later I now work at that exact company. 🚀</description></item><item><title>How many points would you give this story?</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/how-many-points-would-you-give-this-story/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/how-many-points-would-you-give-this-story/</guid><description>It’s time for a mental exercise. You are going to give story points to a user story, that I actually completed. Then I’m going to tell you what I had to do and which issues I ran into.
Background We have a page that lists birthdays for people on the current day, but excluding the current year. In the descending order it then shows their age.
This is nice, but if you want to find out whose birthday is on a specific date, you might have to wait a year for it to come around.</description></item><item><title>My first open source project</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/my-first-open-source-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/my-first-open-source-project/</guid><description>Since november last year I started working on the HabboAPI project. While it is not my first repository, and maybe also not the first serious project (that would be my attempt of the RWS library), it's the first where I went the extra mile to create documentation, tests, continuous integration and Packagist support. I also intend to support this and hope to see other people contribute. So far I have one favourite!</description></item><item><title>Move to Jekyll</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/move-to-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 10:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/move-to-jekyll/</guid><description>So I moved my site to Jekyll and Github Pages.
The reason was that I wanted to get rid of my hosted VPS solution which I didn&amp;rsquo;t use at all. I had great plans of making lots of small websites, but that never really planned out.
I also wanted to get rid of the 500ms page loads of Wordpress (yes, I&amp;rsquo;m sure you can make that better). All I need for my blog is a static website.</description></item><item><title>Dutch Open Hackathon</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/dutch-open-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/dutch-open-hackathon/</guid><description>Last weekend I attended the Dutch Open Hackathon in the UP building (previously known as IJ-toren) in Amsterdam. I went there as part of team 'Pi Ducks'. The team consisted of some colleagues from bol.com (where I started working in July) and a front-end designer we met through Twitter. We had a pretty broad range of skills in one team! Good morning Amsterdam! Billie got hacked! Tired of coding? Take a &amp;amp;#039;flight&amp;amp;#039; to chillzone.</description></item><item><title>meter; the HTML5 element</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/meter-the-html5-element/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/meter-the-html5-element/</guid><description>I'm amazed at how often I still "discover" a new HTML5 element. I say discover because really they're all written down in specs. But then again, who reads specs for their enjoyment? Today I discovered the meter-element (by first discovering the progress-element). They're essentially the same, except that &amp;lt;meter&amp;gt; also adds some sugary deliciousness in the form of colouring. It's here that you should note that IE10 (and higher) only support &amp;lt;progress&amp;gt; at the moment and not &amp;lt;meter&amp;gt;.</description></item><item><title>Piwik, a free open-source analytics tool</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/piwik-a-free-open-source-analytics-tool/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/piwik-a-free-open-source-analytics-tool/</guid><description>I have been using Piwik for a couple of months and I love it. I started using it first at my internship at leadelephant.com, not really as an analytics tool, but more as a data collection tool. The main goal of Piwik is an analytics tool, a direct competitor to Google Analytics. But it's really more than that. Like the data collection method I just mentioned, it could also be a community monitoring tool, which is how we use it at Habbies.</description></item><item><title>Akismet doesn't cut it anymore, utilize Cloudflare against spam</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/akismet-doesnt-cut-it-anymore-utilize-cloudflare-against-spam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/akismet-doesnt-cut-it-anymore-utilize-cloudflare-against-spam/</guid><description>Spam queue in Wordpress I have been noticing a severe drop in spam in my comment queue. I used to have to delete anywhere from 5 to 10 comments a day in the queue with just Akismet. Now there's not one comment.. 99.99% of the time. I didn't really think anything of it until I just realized why this change occurred; I had enabled Cloudflare for my blog. Cloudflare saving requests and thus MBs Cloudflare acts as somewhat of a firewall and CDN in one, it blocks malicious requests and serves cached versions of your blog/site/resources.</description></item><item><title>Road trip to Scandinavia 2013 - Part III</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/road-trip-to-scandinavia-2013-part-iii/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/road-trip-to-scandinavia-2013-part-iii/</guid><description>Day 6: Preikestolen Preikestolen is one of Norway's famous touristtrapslocations, it's a hiking trail that ends at the Preikestolen (Pulpit/Preacher's Chair), a slab of rock hanging over the Lysefjord fjord. There's also the Trolltunga (Devil's Tongue) east of Bergen, which is similar just a lot smaller. But we didn't go there. Preikestolen We had planned the entire day for our trip to the Preikestolen. It had been advertised as a serious achievement, and we weren't that familiar with such hikes.</description></item><item><title>Road trip to Scandinavia 2013 - Part II</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/road-trip-to-scandinavia-2013-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/road-trip-to-scandinavia-2013-part-ii/</guid><description>Day 3: Løkken and Hjørring The next day we drove to the seaside town of Løkken, famous for its candy store and beaches. We arrived early in the afternoon and parked at a big parking lot, for beachgoers. First up; the beach of course. Walked to the beach through the dunes Lovely composition of colours This beach is also famous for its World War II bunkers part of the Atlantic Wall and we could see them in the distance.</description></item><item><title>Road trip to Scandinavia 2013 - Part I</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/road-trip-to-scandinavia-2013-part-i/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/road-trip-to-scandinavia-2013-part-i/</guid><description>Our road trip to Scandinavia I've been wanting to visit Scandinavia for quite a while, I've been to many European countries (Great-Britain, Germany, Belgium, France, Spain, Austria) but never to one of the nordic ones. At a previous internship 2 co-workers of mine have been there and they were absolutely loving it, especially Norway. If you asked me in february where I'd go, I would have probably said the Garda lake in Italy.</description></item><item><title>SocialSpace at ESTEC in Noordwijk</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/socialspace-at-estec-in-noordwijk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/socialspace-at-estec-in-noordwijk/</guid><description>A day worth&amp;#39;s of swag! Yesterday I went to the open day at ESTEC (European Space Research and Technology Centre) in Noordwijk, the Netherlands. This is the ESA (European Space Agency) facility that houses most of the technology research and project development. I'm not even sure what it was anymore, but they have some rooms and utilties over there that even make NASA jealous! However.. I wasn't just at the open day, I was actually invited for the #SocialSpace event hosted by @social4space together with these tweeps.</description></item><item><title>The problem(s) with Open Data</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/the-problems-with-open-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/the-problems-with-open-data/</guid><description>To put this blog post into context; this is written by a 25-year-old developer who uses the Dutch open data (https://data.overheid.nl) and doesn't like to read too much. I rather hack tutorials than read specs and I code stuff for the use of the public, i.e.: data needs to accommodate to the common people. With that out of the way and allowing you to see this from my perspective here goes; the biggest problem(s) with Open Data.</description></item><item><title>My first experience with PagodaBox</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/my-first-experience-with-pagodabox/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/my-first-experience-with-pagodabox/</guid><description>What is PagodaBox This blog post is written about what would now be known as Pagoda v1 and might not be representative. Pagoda Box PagodaBox.com is a Platform as a Service (PaaS) for PHP. They have plans for Ruby and Python, but they're not here yet as of this writing. At Pagoda you can launch components, such as; web (Apache + PHP), database (I know MySQL works for a fact), cache (Memcache or Redis), worker and cron job (beta).</description></item><item><title>Quickly create an empty stdClass object in PHP</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/quickly-create-an-empty-stdclass-object-in-php/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/quickly-create-an-empty-stdclass-object-in-php/</guid><description>I was working on a Laravel project and had to work with a Eloquent ORM object; I then needed to create an empty stdClass object. There's a chance that a person is not known and being lazy I wanted to fill the form anyway with my Person object, so I needed a mockup of that object. &amp;lt;?php $person = (object) array_fill_keys( array(&amp;#39;firstname&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;lastname&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;email&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;photo&amp;#39;), &amp;#39;&amp;#39; ); ?&amp;gt; I'd say this solution is quick and dirty.</description></item><item><title>Get IP range by CIDR notation</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/get-ip-range-by-cidr-notation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/get-ip-range-by-cidr-notation/</guid><description>I wanted to get the IPv4 range of a WHOIS record provided by LACNIC, because unlike other RIRs they don't supply you with the range, but with just a CIDR notation. To make matters worse, they give 'incomplete' net numbers. The only working "CIDR to IP range" function I could find didn't accept it, so I had to sprinkle some magic. &amp;lt;?php $ipdata = explode(&amp;#39;/&amp;#39;, ltrim($incomplete_cidr_notation, &amp;#39;0&amp;#39;)); $dotcount = substr_count($ipdata[0], &amp;#39;.</description></item><item><title>Perfect separator for Shoutcast 7.html file</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/perfect-separator-for-shoutcast-7.html-file/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/perfect-separator-for-shoutcast-7.html-file/</guid><description>To go along nicely with my previous Shoutcast tip, here is a trick to separate the data in the Shoutcast 7.html for displaying. If you, like me, use the Shoutcast 7.html trick to get some quick stats about your stream broadcast but are getting some inconsistencies with parsing the comma-separated input you get, try this: &amp;lt;?php $data = preg_split(&amp;#34;/[,]+/&amp;#34;, $string, 7); ?&amp;gt; A possible outcome would be this: &amp;lt;?php Array ( [0] =&amp;gt; 1 [1] =&amp;gt; 1 [2] =&amp;gt; 1 [3] =&amp;gt; 1000 [4] =&amp;gt; 1 [5] =&amp;gt; 192 [6] =&amp;gt; &amp;#34;Woe, Is Me - Hell, or High Water&amp;#34; ) ?</description></item><item><title>How to programmatically add an IP address to a Shoutcast Reserved IP list in PHP</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/how-to-programmatically-add-an-ip-address-to-a-shoutcast-reserved-ip-list-in-php/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/how-to-programmatically-add-an-ip-address-to-a-shoutcast-reserved-ip-list-in-php/</guid><description>Pretty semantic title, huh? But that's basically what this is all about. Shoutcast logo If you have a Shoutcast host that is set to private, only people whose IP address in the RIP list (Reserved IP) can access your stream. A lot of free Shoutcast server providers do this, to make it a bit less profitable to free ride their services. Let's have a quick look at the code and then analyze it to understand what it's doing.</description></item><item><title>array_push_insert: Push new value into array with PHP</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/array_push_insert-push-new-value-into-array-with-php/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/array_push_insert-push-new-value-into-array-with-php/</guid><description>This blogpost is for historical purposes. There is a better way with array_splice. At work today, my colleague needed to add, or rather 'insert', a value into an existing array AND on a specific index. This because we fed it into a JS table sorter, once we pulled it through json_encode(). So what we really required: array_push_insert
We couldn't find any existing Array function at php.net, so I decided to make my own version.</description></item><item><title>T-Mobile traffic through http://1.2.3.12</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/t-mobile-traffic-through-1-2-3-12/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/t-mobile-traffic-through-1-2-3-12/</guid><description>I'm at a place where there's no internet, so I hooked up my T-Mobile G1 (an HTC Dream) to my laptop through the PdaNet app. When I was browsing a site, I noticed an image that wasn't working. So I opened it up in a new tab, where it seemed to work again, but I then noticed the URL. The http:// part of the original source was dropped and replaced by http://1.</description></item><item><title>Posts archive</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/posts/archive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/posts/archive/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>