<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>personal on Gerben Jacobs</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/tags/personal/</link><description>Recent content in personal on Gerben Jacobs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My ROI stock portfolio experiment</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/my-roi-stock-portfolio-experiment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/my-roi-stock-portfolio-experiment/</guid><description>After reading a bit about multiple well-known investors mentioning how important Return On Invested Capital is, I decided to generate a small portfolio (actually a pie within Trading212) with some metrics.
I used finviz to screen and since they don&amp;rsquo;t have ROIC, I used Return On Investment (ROI). This is a different metric but is the closest option there is. My screening options were as follows:
ROI of 25% or higher Net profit margin of 25% or higher Market cap of 2 billion or higher Positive dividend Average trading volume of 1 million So the important values are the ROI and net profit margins.</description></item><item><title>First month at GitHub</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/first-month-at-github/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/first-month-at-github/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a month since I joined GitHub in February of 2022. I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying myself a lot, but I&amp;rsquo;m also not sure if the reality has set in completely.
In 2014 I started my first tech job and remember that I went to a conference and got GitHub stickers, they were awesome and all ended up on my MacBook. Eight years later I now work at that exact company. 🚀</description></item><item><title>Dutch Open Hackathon</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/dutch-open-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/dutch-open-hackathon/</guid><description>Last weekend I attended the Dutch Open Hackathon in the UP building (previously known as IJ-toren) in Amsterdam. I went there as part of team 'Pi Ducks'. The team consisted of some colleagues from bol.com (where I started working in July) and a front-end designer we met through Twitter. We had a pretty broad range of skills in one team! Good morning Amsterdam! Billie got hacked! Tired of coding? Take a &amp;amp;#039;flight&amp;amp;#039; to chillzone.</description></item><item><title>Road trip to Scandinavia 2013 - Part III</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/road-trip-to-scandinavia-2013-part-iii/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/road-trip-to-scandinavia-2013-part-iii/</guid><description>Day 6: Preikestolen Preikestolen is one of Norway's famous touristtrapslocations, it's a hiking trail that ends at the Preikestolen (Pulpit/Preacher's Chair), a slab of rock hanging over the Lysefjord fjord. There's also the Trolltunga (Devil's Tongue) east of Bergen, which is similar just a lot smaller. But we didn't go there. Preikestolen We had planned the entire day for our trip to the Preikestolen. It had been advertised as a serious achievement, and we weren't that familiar with such hikes.</description></item><item><title>Road trip to Scandinavia 2013 - Part II</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/road-trip-to-scandinavia-2013-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/road-trip-to-scandinavia-2013-part-ii/</guid><description>Day 3: Løkken and Hjørring The next day we drove to the seaside town of Løkken, famous for its candy store and beaches. We arrived early in the afternoon and parked at a big parking lot, for beachgoers. First up; the beach of course. Walked to the beach through the dunes Lovely composition of colours This beach is also famous for its World War II bunkers part of the Atlantic Wall and we could see them in the distance.</description></item><item><title>Road trip to Scandinavia 2013 - Part I</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/road-trip-to-scandinavia-2013-part-i/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/road-trip-to-scandinavia-2013-part-i/</guid><description>Our road trip to Scandinavia I've been wanting to visit Scandinavia for quite a while, I've been to many European countries (Great-Britain, Germany, Belgium, France, Spain, Austria) but never to one of the nordic ones. At a previous internship 2 co-workers of mine have been there and they were absolutely loving it, especially Norway. If you asked me in february where I'd go, I would have probably said the Garda lake in Italy.</description></item><item><title>SocialSpace at ESTEC in Noordwijk</title><link>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/socialspace-at-estec-in-noordwijk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.gerbenjacobs.nl/socialspace-at-estec-in-noordwijk/</guid><description>A day worth&amp;#39;s of swag! Yesterday I went to the open day at ESTEC (European Space Research and Technology Centre) in Noordwijk, the Netherlands. This is the ESA (European Space Agency) facility that houses most of the technology research and project development. I'm not even sure what it was anymore, but they have some rooms and utilties over there that even make NASA jealous! However.. I wasn't just at the open day, I was actually invited for the #SocialSpace event hosted by @social4space together with these tweeps.</description></item></channel></rss>